Guide to the Program in Education Records, 1985-Ongoing UA.07.06.0001
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Program in Education records
1985-Ongoing
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Duke University. Program in Education
UA.07.06.0001
0.75 Linear Feet
The Duke University Program in Education provides opportunities for undergraduates to connect their liberal art studies and the academic work of their major with rigorous intellectual examination of the issues confronting schools, children, and communities. This collection contains reports, inromation regarding the Winfred Quinton Holton Prize for educational research, including prize winning papers and other records.
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the University Archives to use this collection.
For a period of twenty-five years from the origin of the material, permission in writing from the office of origin and the University Archivist is required for use. After twenty-five years, records that have been processed may be consulted with the permission of the University Archivist.
Provenance
The Program in Education Records were received by the University Archives as a transfer beginning in 1993-present.
Historical Note
The Duke University Program in Education provides opportunities for undergraduates to connect their liberal art studies and the academic work of their major with rigorous intellectual examination of the issues confronting schools, children, and communities. In 1924, under the direction of and with an endowment from James B. Duke, Trinity College became Duke University. In the Indenture of Trust, J.B. Duke insisted that the training of teachers be among Duke's primary missions.
Collection Overview
This collection contains reports, information regarding the Winfred Quinton Holton Prize for educational research, including prize winning papers and other records.
Duke University. Program in Education; Duke University -- Students
- Specialty Area Report, TCAS, 1992 (2 folders) (Box 1)
- Institutional Report, National Council for Accreditation of Teacher Education, 1992 (2 folders) (Box 1)
- Faculty Vitae, National Council for Accreditation of Teacher Education, 1992 (Box 1)
- Duke/Durham Fellows Seminar, 1985-1990 (Box 1)
- W. Q. Holton Award, 2000 (Box 1)
- Holton Award-winning paper by Lee, 2000 (Box 1)
- Holton Award-winning paper by Mitchell, 2000 (Box 1)
- Holton Award-winning paper by Riley, Sapperstein, Riley and Ling, 2000 (Box 1)
- Holton Prize, 2009 (Box 1)
- Holton Prize, 2010 (2 folders) (Box 1)
- Holton Prize, 2011 (2 folders) (Box 1)
- Holton Prize, 2012 (Box 1)
- Holton Prize, 2013; 4 folders (Box 2)
- Holton Prize, 2015; 3 folders (Box 2)